Fantasy...beyond your imagination
The Lord of the Rings is a adventure, animation,
fantasy film directed by Ralph Bakshi.
Young Hobbit Frodo Baggins is thrown into an amazing adventure when he's tasked
with destroying the One Ring, created by the dark lord Sauron.
Frodo must travel in a small fellowship of nine warriors and accomplices.
But it won't be an easy journey for the Fellowship of the Ring, on
the ultimate quest to rid Middle-earth of evil.
Frodo (voice), played by Christopher Guard.
Gandalf (voice), played by William Squire.
Sam (voice), played by Michael Scholes.
Aragorn (voice), played by John Hurt.
Merry (voice), played by Simon Chandler.
Pippin (voice), played by Dominic Guard.
The Lord of the Rings is a 1978 animated epic fantasy film directed by
Ralph Bakshi from a screenplay by Chris Conkling and Peter S.
It is based on the novel of the same name by J.
Tolkien, adapting from the volumes The Fellowship
of the Ring and The Two Towers.
Set in Middle-earth, the film follows a group of fantasy races—Hobbits, Men, an Elf, a Dwarf and a wizard—who
form a fellowship to destroy a magical ring made by the Dark Lord Sauron, the main antagonist.
Bakshi encountered Tolkien's writing early in his career.
He had made several attempts to produce The Lord of the Rings as an animated film before
producer Saul Zaentz and distributor United Artists provided funding.
The film is notable for its extensive use of rotoscoping, a technique in which
scenes are first shot in live-action, then traced onto animation cels.
It uses a hybrid of traditional cel animation and
rotoscoped live-action footage.
The Lord of the Rings was released in the United States on November
15, 1978, and in the United Kingdom on July 5, 1979.
Although the film received mixed reviews from critics, and hostility from disappointed
viewers who felt that it was incomplete, it was a financial success.
There was no official sequel to cover the remainder of the story.
However, the film has retained a cult following and was a major
inspiration for New Zealand filmmaker Peter Jackson.
The film explores themes of mission, based on
novel or book, elves, dwarf, troll.
The tone is dark.